<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ELECTRA | Hao Meng - Academic Homepage</title><link>/tag/electra/</link><atom:link href="/tag/electra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ELECTRA</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Hao Meng. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/icon_hu_a9296fd8e02a9164.png</url><title>ELECTRA</title><link>/tag/electra/</link></image><item><title>The context-oriented system based on ELECTRA for solving math word problem</title><link>/publication/context-oriented-electra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/context-oriented-electra/</guid><description>&lt;p>This paper introduces a context-oriented system that utilizes ELECTRA, a pre-trained language model, to enhance the understanding and solving of mathematical word problems. The system focuses on capturing contextual information to improve problem comprehension and solution accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-contributions">Key Contributions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ELECTRA Integration&lt;/strong>: Effective use of ELECTRA for mathematical problem understanding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Context-Oriented Approach&lt;/strong>: Emphasis on contextual information for better problem comprehension&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>System Architecture&lt;/strong>: Comprehensive system design for math word problem solving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Evaluation&lt;/strong>: Thorough evaluation of the proposed approach&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The proposed system includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Context Analysis&lt;/strong>: Deep understanding of problem context using ELECTRA&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Semantic Processing&lt;/strong>: Enhanced semantic understanding of mathematical concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Problem Decomposition&lt;/strong>: Breaking down complex problems into manageable components&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Solution Generation&lt;/strong>: Systematic approach to generating mathematical solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Evaluation Framework&lt;/strong>: Comprehensive evaluation of system performance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This work demonstrates the effectiveness of transformer-based language models in educational applications, particularly in the domain of automated mathematical problem solving.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>