<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Math Word Problems | 孟皓的学术主页</title><link>/tag/math-word-problems/</link><atom:link href="/tag/math-word-problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Math Word Problems</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 孟皓. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/icon_hu_e747e089a9e68c83.png</url><title>Math Word Problems</title><link>/tag/math-word-problems/</link></image><item><title>A bi-channel math word problem solver with understanding and reasoning</title><link>/publication/bi-channel-solver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/bi-channel-solver/</guid><description>&lt;p>This paper introduces a novel bi-channel architecture for solving mathematical word problems that separates understanding and reasoning processes. The system leverages two distinct channels to handle different aspects of problem solving, leading to improved performance and interpretability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-contributions">Key Contributions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bi-channel Architecture&lt;/strong>: Novel dual-channel approach for math problem solving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Understanding Channel&lt;/strong>: Dedicated channel for problem comprehension&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reasoning Channel&lt;/strong>: Specialized channel for mathematical reasoning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Integration Strategy&lt;/strong>: Effective combination of understanding and reasoning outputs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Enhancement&lt;/strong>: Improved accuracy and interpretability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The proposed system consists of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Understanding Channel&lt;/strong>: Processes natural language to extract mathematical concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reasoning Channel&lt;/strong>: Performs mathematical reasoning and computation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Feature Extraction&lt;/strong>: Comprehensive feature extraction from problem text&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Channel Integration&lt;/strong>: Fusion of understanding and reasoning outputs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Solution Generation&lt;/strong>: Final solution synthesis from both channels&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="experimental-results">Experimental Results&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The bi-channel approach demonstrates superior performance compared to single-channel baselines, showing the effectiveness of separating understanding and reasoning processes in mathematical problem solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This work contributes to the field of educational AI by providing a more structured and interpretable approach to automated mathematical problem solving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The context-oriented system based on ELECTRA for solving math word problem</title><link>/publication/context-oriented-electra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/context-oriented-electra/</guid><description>&lt;p>This paper introduces a context-oriented system that utilizes ELECTRA, a pre-trained language model, to enhance the understanding and solving of mathematical word problems. The system focuses on capturing contextual information to improve problem comprehension and solution accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-contributions">Key Contributions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ELECTRA Integration&lt;/strong>: Effective use of ELECTRA for mathematical problem understanding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Context-Oriented Approach&lt;/strong>: Emphasis on contextual information for better problem comprehension&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>System Architecture&lt;/strong>: Comprehensive system design for math word problem solving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Evaluation&lt;/strong>: Thorough evaluation of the proposed approach&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The proposed system includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Context Analysis&lt;/strong>: Deep understanding of problem context using ELECTRA&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Semantic Processing&lt;/strong>: Enhanced semantic understanding of mathematical concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Problem Decomposition&lt;/strong>: Breaking down complex problems into manageable components&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Solution Generation&lt;/strong>: Systematic approach to generating mathematical solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Evaluation Framework&lt;/strong>: Comprehensive evaluation of system performance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This work demonstrates the effectiveness of transformer-based language models in educational applications, particularly in the domain of automated mathematical problem solving.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>